https://www.dcu.ie/info/regulations/privacy.shtml

Skip to main content
Information - Dublin City University Privacy Statement
Dublin City University Privacy StatementThis statement relates to Dublin City University's privacy practices in connection with University websites. The University is not responsible for the content or privacy practices of other websites. External links to other websites are not always clearly identifiable as such. Within the Dublin City University domain you may find websites over which the University has no editorial responsibility or control. Such sites can include the websites of student organisations etc. While the University encourages compliance with this web privacy statement at such sites, please consult the privacy statements of individual sites or contact the persons responsible for those sites, in order to understand the policies and practices under which they operate.General statementDublin City University fully respects your right to privacy and actively seeks to preserve the privacy rights of those who share information with the University. The University will not collect any personal information about you on this website without your permission save in cases where the University is required by law to do so (e.g. the investigation of a criminal offence or a breach of the University's policies, procedures or guidelines). Any personal information which you volunteer to the University will be treated with the highest standards of security and confidentiality, in accordance with the Data Protection Acts 1988 to 2018. The University's Data Privacy Policy, available at the link below, documents the University's application of the Data Protection Principles and the manner in which data is processed across the university. DCU Data Privacy PolicyCollection and use of personal informationDublin City University does not collect any personal data about you on this website, apart from information which you volunteer (for example by e-mailing the University). Any information, which you provide in this way, is not made available to any third party - other than those working with the University on normal University business, and is used by the University only in line with the purpose for which you provided it.Collection and use of technical informationCookies may be used by the DCU website to collect non-personal information about how visitors use our website or to remember display preferences.  Temporary session cookies may also be used in some areas to enable specific functionality (e.g. portal pages).  Session cookies are deleted once you close your browser session.
Occasionally for the purposes of DCU online services we must pass some cookie information to third parties.  These cookies may persist after your browser session has ended.  This information will not include any of your personal data or information from which you will be readily identifiable. This information may be used for evaluating your use of the website, compiling reports on website activity for DCU and providing other services relating to website activity and internet usage.  It is stored and used in the aggregate only and is not used to obtain personal data or to contact you personally, but instead to improve website services.  DCU actively seeks to preserve user privacy in any interaction with third parties.
Some areas within the DCU website use online data entry forms to collect personal information from web visitors who choose to identify themselves for the purpose of transacting e-commerce or receiving products, services, or information.  Areas within DCU that collect data of any type are required to abide by our Privacy Statement. We request no more information than is required to fulfill the purpose for which the information is being collected.Technical details in connection with visits to this website may be logged by the University's internet service provider for accounting and auditing purposes. This technical information will be used only for statistical and other administrative purposes. You should note that technical details, which the University cannot associate with any identifiable individual, do not constitute `personal data' for the purposes of the Data Protection Acts 1988 to 2018.Personal Data RightsYou have a number of rights under perosnal data protection legislation. For further information on these please refer to the guide below.Data Subject Rights Procedure - Public.For further information on personal data matters, including the contact details for the DCU Data Protection Officer, please refer to the University's Data Protection webpage at the link below. Data Protection UnitThis statement explains the Internet Privacy policy that the University has adopted for its websites. However, in legal terms it shall not be construed as a contractual undertaking. The University reserves the right to review and amend this statement at any time without notice.
